<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sir Gradient&#39;s Descent into Madness</title>
    <link>https://nicovaras.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sir Gradient&#39;s Descent into Madness</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 11:43:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicovaras.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emoji Journey: Exploring Sentiments with the Power of TPUs 🎉</title>
      <link>https://nicovaras.github.io/posts/emoji-tpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 11:43:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicovaras.github.io/posts/emoji-tpu/</guid>
      <description>Notebook: here
Today, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share a fun mini project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on 🎉. I came across a dataset of tweets with emojis on Kaggle and thought, &amp;ldquo;Why not try to do something with this?&amp;rdquo; 🤔. The project started out pretty standard, but as there was a ton of data and my architectures were quite large (I tried transformers again without success - yet again 😅), it quickly became challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Painting with pixels: Variational Autoencoders applied to art</title>
      <link>https://nicovaras.github.io/posts/vae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicovaras.github.io/posts/vae/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This time around, I felt the urge to explore the world of VAEs (Variational Autoencoders). These autoencoders can be used for generating new data, but we&amp;rsquo;ll get into that in a bit. I wanted to avoid the all-too-common MNIST example, so I opted for a more adventurous route: generating ⭐art!⭐ This experiment could either be a smashing success or an entertaining disaster. So, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into this artistic adventure with VAEs&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music generation with GRUs</title>
      <link>https://nicovaras.github.io/posts/music-generation-gru/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 19:16:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicovaras.github.io/posts/music-generation-gru/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Hello, and welcome to my blog! I wanted to share with you a mini-project that&amp;rsquo;s been on my mind for some time.
You see, I have a huge collection of MIDI files from various bands that I&amp;rsquo;ve used to learn guitar (actually, they&amp;rsquo;re Guitar Pro files, but converting them to MIDI is easy enough). With such musical data, I knew there was potential for an interesting machine learning project. There are countless things to explore, such as genre classification or instrument recognition, but I decided to focus on music generation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
